Guide to the Athletic Teams' Records, 1870 - 2007
Athletic Teams' Records, 1870 - 2007
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Wesleyan University. Dept. of Physical Education.
1999-65
1.5
2
The Athletic Teams' Records contain a number of volumes that document personal and team records for Wesleyan teams including both Wesleyan records and intercollegiate athletic records set during athletic contests. Some volumes contain detailed scoring information and statistics from teams including baseball and football. Other sports represented in the collection include golf, hockey, lacrosse, basketball, swimming, boating, softball, and tennis.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Transferred from the Department of Physical Education in 1999.
Additional material donated by Erhard Konerding in 2007.
Collection Overview
This collection contains a number of volumes that document personal and team records for Wesleyan teams including both Wesleyan records and intercollegiate athletic records set during athletic contests. Some volumes contain detailed scoring information and statistics from teams including baseball and football. There are also 2006 football playbooks, and a 207-2007 Student-Athlete Handbook. Other sports represented in the collection include golf, hockey, lacrosse, basketball, swimming, boating, softball, and tennis. Some financial records and correspodence related to individual teams is also present. Many of these volumes were created before the founding of the Wesleyan Athletic Council, when each team had its own supporting and administrative organization, and complement some portions of the Athletic Council Records, which are also housed in the Wesleyan University Archives.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Basketball.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Baseball.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Football.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Sports.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Swimming.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Tennis.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Golf.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Hockey.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Lacrosse.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Softball.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.) --Boating.; Athletics --Connecticut --Middletown --20th century.
Related Material
All of the following collections are available in Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University:
Agallian Base Ball Club Records, 1865-1869
Athletic Council Records, 1903-1958
Athletic Department Artifacts, 1872-
Athletic Facilities Blueprints, ca. 1990s-
Football Programs Collection, 1891-
University photograph collections
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - Department of Physical Education, Athletic Records, Volume I, Spring Sports: Golf/Hockey/Lacrosse, 1927-1980 (Box 1)
  - Department of Physical Education, Athletic Records, Volume II, Winter Sports: Basketball/Swimming, 1901-1980
  - Baseball
    - Record book, 1862-1917
    - Scorebook, 1899
    - Scorebook, 1900
    - Scorebook, 1903
    - Base-Ball Department, Wesleyan Athletic Association, Cash Book, 1911-1912
    - Scorebook, 1928-1931
    - Scorebook, 1938-1939
    - Freshman baseball scorebook, 1937-1941
  - Basketball scorebooks, 1931-1934, 1941-1942
    These scorebooks are in four volumes.
  - Boating Records, Trophy Room, Fayerweather Gymnasium, 1870-1884
    This item is a ledger book.
  - Football Association receipts and scrapbook, 1891-1896
  - Football Association correspondence, 1889-1891
  - Football Department, Wesleyan Athletic Association, Cash Book, 1911-1913 (Box 2)
    This cash book is in two volumes.
  - Softball Scorebook, 1944
  - Tennis Department, Wesleyan Athletic Association, Cash Book, 1911-1912
  - Tennis Department, Wesleyan Athletic Association, Cash Book, 1911-1912
  - 3 Football Playbooks, 2006
  - Student-Athlete Handbook, 2006-2007